

Bryan Jin

Senior Software Engineer

Contact

30, July 1990

hereis.topdev@gmail.com

+17722492462

6 VERDUN ROAD, Singapore

live:.cid.6937c75f6bb27225

Education

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep 2011 – August 2015

National University of Singapore

About

I'm Bryan, a senior software engineer with over 8 years of experience in software engineering & web development.

I'm highly organized, self- motivated, and proficient with both frontend & backend technologies.

I'm seeking to use my hard won technical and programming skills alongside proven project management to improve quality, cost and time metrics for web application development.

I am a great communicator, enjoy collaborating within teams where I bring my creativity in problem solving, drive and efficiency to the table. I believe in being a self-starter, thinking critically and taking accountability for my work and responsibilities, while inspiring the same in people around me

Programming languages

JavaScript / Typescript PHP Solidity Python Ruby

Technical Skills

React / Vue / Angular Next.js / GatsBy.js / Nuxt.js Ruby on Rails / Laravel Node.js / Express.js / Nest.js Koa / Cypress / Selenium MySQL / MongoDB / PostgreSQL Rest API / GraphQL(Relay, Apollo) Docker / AWS / Git / CI / CD Blockchain / Ethereum





























Work Experience

Kickstarter, Brooklyn, New York

December 2021 - Present

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (MERN & ROR Stack)

- Worked closely and collaboratively within a cross functional team of product managers, designers, engineers as well as stakeholders.
- Iteratively researched, experimented, and developed products and features to solve real problems for kickstarter creators and backers, helped drive the technical direction of the kickstarter platform and product.
- Refactored old ROR framework with legacy codes and built features with modern frameworks like React, Redux, Apollo, and Typescript, all backed by GraphQL API, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, AWS EC2.
- Mentored, coached and shared knowledge with other team members and across the engineering organization.

EnvyTheme Middletown, Delaware

November 2019 – December 2021

FULL STACK ENGINEER (LARAVEL | JAM Stack)

- Developed, tested and deployed high-quality code for EnvyTheme's products including React, Next.js, Vue, Angular and Laravel templates
- Troubleshoot, debugged and optimized the code to improve performance and scalability, created and maintained technical documentation.
- Contributed to 400% increase in theme sales while simultaneously decreasing support requests thanks to bug free code and thorough documentation, resulting in a considerable increase in annual revenue.

Virtus Ventures LLC, Ohio

December 2018 – October 2019

SENIOR WEB AND MOBILE APP DEVELOPER | MERN STACK

- Designed, developed and deployed 5 full-stack web applications and mobile apps, generating revenue in excess of \$2M annually.
- Worked directly with stakeholders in Virtus Ventures to stay on budget and time manage while meeting client needs.
- Acted as the main point of contact responsible for React, Next.js, Node.js, React Native and Flutter with various clients.
- Improved SEO on several existing MERN stack products by improving the page speed.
- Gained experience with GCM and AWS Amplify while implementing a Real time chat feature and database.

Appalope LLC, Peachtree City, GA

January 2018 – November 2018

SENIOR MOBILE APP DEVELOPER | IONIC

- Building user interfaces and designing the methodology, structure and architecture for the projects complex data visualization requirements.
- Creating Angular 5 and Ionic 3 Native builds for single model view solutions
- Working with data modelling for variable Ecommerce products in the medical field.
- Implementing RESTful API services for creating, retrieving, updating, and deleting data in JSON.

Appalope LLC, Peachtree City, GA

January 2017 – December 2017

WEB DEVELOPER | MEAN STACK

- Led the end-to-end development process of multiple software applications and websites.
- Created Healthcare web applications to connect customers with the most trusted sources of generic and brand medicine suppliers in the world.
- Designed, implemented, documented, and successfully deployed warehouse integration code using Node.js, Angular, Express, MongoDB.
- Structured several affiliate systems which used a centralized database.

Appalope LLC, Peachtree City, GA

November 2015 – December 2016

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

- \bullet Translated 50+ PSD page designs into responsive, SEO-friendly web pages with high accessibility.
- Under the supervision of senior software engineer, participated in revamping the legacy COdeIgniter website into Laravel, ensuring all the features are correctly working.
- Optimized 10+ complex SQL queries, which decreased the page load time by 40%.

 $Bryan \ J. \ _{\text{Senior Software Engineer}}$

Contact

hereis.topdev@gmail.com